Hey everybody and welcome back to the
alliance. I am Chris. I'm here with
another three questions which is where
we do a series where we explore how God
is using women in the PCA. And we are
here with one of my favorite people. She
does all kinds of things. Her name is
Katie Psky and I'm going to let her
introduce herself. Tell us about
yourself. I am Katie. I'm married to
Chris. Uh we live here in
Not this one, right? Although I will say
I had to change on my phone. There were
a couple times uh long ago I texted you
and it meant to text my husband. So
you're see Gordon. Yes.
Married to Chris Pski um who's a pastor
at uh Trinity Church in Kirkwood,
Missouri. We have three kids and one uh
son-in-law. So Ella and Cooper live in
Chattanooga. Um Jonathan lives with us.
Uh he works in sales and Lily is uh
almost 17, a junior in high school. Um
and already ready to go to college, so
next year should be interesting. But um
which is crazy because in my head your
children are like in middle and
elementary school, but somehow decided
to just keep growing. It happens. So I
would love to hear if you could tell us
first question, what's your little
corner of the kingdom? Tell us some
about it and what you do there. Yeah.
So, I serve as the music director and
special events coordinator at Trinity,
uh, where Chris is, uh, the pastor. Um,
my journey was a little bit unexpected.
Uh, I played piano in high school, but I
hid it because I wanted to be known as
an athlete. I was a basketball player.
Uh, but Sandra McCracken, who many know
led our school's worship band, and, uh,
she knew I played, so she encouraged me
to step into that role. and uh leading
in that way was just a really formative
experience for me. So I decided to
pursue music in college and also try to
play basketball. But um an injury ended
my basketball career early in college
and led to just a really difficult
season of depression. So I abandoned
music altogether entirely and I shifted
to an English major. Uh that led to a
passion for writing which actually
opened up many doors for me through the
years. So, I'm grateful for that. Uh,
but I avoided piano uh for years. And
then when my husband planted our church
here in St. Louis, they needed a
pianist. Uh, so playing again kind of
just rekindled my love for worship. Um,
and then in 2017, I officially became
Trinity's part-time music director, a
role which now has evolved into a
full-time position and has expanded into
other leadership and service
opportunities. So, it's just been a joy
to serve where God has placed me. I'm so
grateful. After not saying yes for a
long
time like made you do it. Yes. Oh, I
love to hear it. Yes. Um and she's not
going to say this about herself, but
Katie writes wonderfully. She has a
blog. She's writing
articles. She has lots of things that
are good for all of us that she decided
to be an English major. Okay. If you
could tell us one story about how you've
seen God use you or the ministry you're
involved in lately, what would that
story be? Yeah. Um, well, I first have
to just say that as a music director, I
see my job as ushering our congregation
to Jesus through worship. So, my measure
of success is pretty simple. Did the
people sing out? I always think of Psalm
34:3, magnify the Lord together. So
fostering that environment is is my
mission and I I love doing that through
what I always call Christ centered and
hospitable worship. Um and lately I've
seen God working in and through the m
musicians at our church. Um just they're
growing in understanding of Christc
centered hospitable worship. And it's
just it's inspiring for me to see their
willingness to serve the body week in
and week out by using their instruments
and their voices. and not because
they're paid, but because they love
worship and they desire to lead our
congregation well in it. So, it's just
it's inspiring to me. And then our
annual concert series, uh, which has
been just a really powerful outreach
tool, um, has exposed our congregation
to all sorts of different musical
talents, and I've loved that. Uh, we had
one attendee share how a song of lament
that he heard at a recent concert
resonated with um he resonated with with
with it because he was going through
some workplace struggles and it just
reminded me of how God speaks to us
through all kinds of music in all kinds
of situations. So, not just kind of the
joyful songs or or joyful situations,
uh, but songs of lament, songs about
work like in this in this case. Um, but
his common grace is seen and and
magnified in the work that I'm in. And
it's it's a powerful testimony to me and
I think to others. Oh, for sure. It's
really encouraging. Yeah. I mean, even
just being at one of the concerts was
lovely for so many reasons. Okay, third
question. What can we who are listening
and watching on the outside your PCA
brothers and sisters, how can we
encourage you in the work that you do to
keep going and to keep putting in the
hours and the time and the effort? What
would be helpful? You know, three three
things came to mind um when I saw that
question. Very brief. The first is um
just to value and support musicians and
artists in your church. uh recognize
their work, pray for them on Sunday
mornings, name their vocation um and and
maybe create spaces for them to to grow
or to contribute a and in all different
ages. Um I know of one church who has a
hallway. It's so cool. um walking down
it, but it's a hallway dedicated to
their artists. And then what they do is
they display differing works throughout
the year. And it's just it's a beautiful
way of saying to these artists um that
the talents that God has given them can
be used for his glory to advance the
kingdom. So recognize the artists and
musicians. Um and the second thing I'd
say is broaden your perspective when
hiring music directors. Um well it it is
true that you have to have um musical
ability right and formal music training
is beneficial but I would say what's
equally important and I might even argue
more important is theological depth
leadership and understanding of
congregational worship.
So many of the um job descriptions that
I see require a a music degree and um
assume that if you have a music degree,
you will do well leading worship and the
and the that that's not always the case.
It doesn't one doesn't necessarily
translate with the other. So churches
might just consider broadening their
perspective if they're looking um or a
music or worship leader. Um and then the
last thing, this is just more personal.
Um I I just I'd encourage um my brothers
and sisters to consider compensating
their pastor's wives who take on
significant ministry roles in their
church. Um I know that's kind of a
rabbit trail. It's a little bit
different than my job per se. Um but
there are there are a lot of um pastors
wives who have to work to support their
families and if they they are called to
serve and especially if they feel a
personal call to ministry even outside
of what they're already doing alongside
their husbands um their labor should be
acknowledged. So um just something to to
consider. I I did what I did for a long
time alongside of my husband until um
the session said,
"Hey, we should make you uh an official
part of the staff," which I'm grateful.
I'm glad you're not the first to say it
either in this series. It's helpful to
hear. Thank you for your time, Katie
Pski. Thank you for what you're doing.
We appreciate you. Thanks for the
conversation.